yourhormones.info 2016-09-29

# Society for Endocrinology | Disclaimer

### Privacy Policy

All personal information transmitted or otherwise submitted to the Society for Endocrinology via this web site shall only be used by the Society to the extent permitted by applicable legislation, specifically the Data Protection Act 1998.

### Information about our organisation and website

Modern information and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of an organisation like the Society for Endocrinology.

The Society is dedicated to ensuring that your privacy is protected in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

This statement explains the privacy practices of the Society, and may change from time to time so please check back periodically. Whilst the Society is committed to this privacy policy you may find that only parts of it relate to you depending on what services you are dealing with.

### **What information is collected about me by the Society for Endocrinology and how**?

The Society collects information about you for the following purposes:

  * Technical administration of the website 
  * Research and development 
  * Society membership 
  * Abstract submission
  * Event registration, booking and feedback 
  * Formal membership mailings – postal and email 
  * Marketing (where we have your consent for this purpose)
  * Contact by the media (where we have your consent for this purpose).

Information on the last two items will be collected upon application.  We will not ask for this information on an annual basis but will rely upon you to let us know if your choices change.

The Society therefore collects, uses and disseminates the personal information that is provided to us only in accordance with the policies outlined in this document. We may keep your information for a reasonable period for these purposes.

We collect the personal data that you may volunteer while using the following services: membership renewal, event registration, submission of abstracts and every time you email us your details.

### What non-personally identifiable information does the Society collect?

The Society may also collect non-personally identifiable information (that is, information that does not specifically identify you), such as aggregate use statistics. We may collect some basic information about your computer and internet connections, including: your Internet Protocol Address, your operating system (eg Windows or Mac), your browser software (eg Netscape or Internet Explorer), your Internet Service Provider (eg AOL or AT&T), your geographic location. The Society collects this information to improve its own website services, for example, to diagnose problems with our server, or administering our website.

### As a member, how is my information stored by the Society for Endocrinology?

The information you provide to the Society is stored on the Society’s own internal system and database and on a secure remote server. These systems are protected by industry-recognised secure methods and only Society staff or others acting on our behalf will be authorised to access the information you provide to us. 

### What else should I know about my privacy when using other websites?

Our membership websites enable Society members to communicate with other members and to post information to be accessed by members. The Society web site may contain links to other websites but the Society is not responsible for their respective privacy practices, content or data capture policies (eg cookies). 

### Children's privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children. 

### Disclosure

We do not disclose your personal data to other organisations other than as necessary for the purposes for which you have supplied your information. However, for the purpose of data integrity, information may be made available to other societies managed by BioScientifica Ltd, the Society for Endocrinology’s trading company, including those outside the UK, but only where they comply with similar data protection principles. An example would be where you provide an address change of one society; this will be used to update your address for any other society of which you are a member where BioScientifica also handles membership. In certain circumstances BioScientifica will offer you the means to disallow consent to disclosure throughout BioScientifica services by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected or by contacting our Data Protection Officer. Otherwise by providing us with your information you consent to such disclosure.

We may also engage third parties to process information on our behalf subject to appropriate security protections being in place.

We may also disclose personal data in order to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation or if necessary for legal proceedings.

In order for you to attend an event delivered by a partner organisation, it may be necessary to exchange some contact information with them.

### Confidentiality/security

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or any wireless network can be 100% secure, although we do employ industry standard techniques to secure your data. We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: 

  * unauthorised access 
  * improper use or disclosure 
  * unauthorised modification 
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss 

### Cookies

When you visit the Society for Endocrinology website, The Society for Endocrinology sends your computer a small file called a cookie, which we can access when you visit our site in future. The Society for Endocrinology collect this information to help our website run smoothly, and to analyse general trends in the way our users interact with the website (such as the most popular content) so that we can ensure the website meets the demands of our users.

To analyse our cookie data, The Society for Endocrinology use a third party service provided by Google Inc called Google Analytics. Google Analytics does not associate your anonymous cookie data with any other identifiable data that Google may hold about you.

Further details on cookies, and how to de-activate them, can be found at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

#### Cookies that might be used on this site

Cookie | Purpose  
---|---  
__gads | Targeting/Advertising  
__utma | Performance  
__utmb | Performance  
__utmc | Performance  
__utmt | Performance  
__utmz | Performance  
.ASPXAUTH | User authentication  
cb-enabled | Cookie preference  
km_ni | Social media integration  
.doubleclick.net | Targeting/Advertising  
_atuvc | Social media integration  
_atuvs | Social media integration  
  
### Members’ security precautions 

Your account information and profile are password-protected so that you are the only member who has access to this information. 

As a member of the Society, you will be able to view the contact details of other members via the members’ directory.  This directory is for members’ use only and on no account may your password or any details be divulged to any other person.  A breach of this will be referred to Council of Management for their decision on appropriate action. 

Remember to log out from your registered area and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our site. 

Ultimately you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. 

### How do I hide my details from other members? 

The terms and conditions of membership of the Society require your details to appear in the members’ directory.

However, you may contact the secretariat if you wish to discuss your concerns.

If you have provided a home address as your mailing address, only your name and email address will appear to other members.

### How can I access my information?

You can ask us, by: 

  * sending postal mail to Data Protection Officer, Society for Endocrinology, 22 Apex House, Woodlands, Bradley Stoke, Bristol, BS32 4JT, UK 
  * contacting our Data Protection Officer (see link below)

We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you, and to which you are entitled under the Data Protection Act 1998 - although we may require proof of your identity before doing so. We may charge you an administration fee of £10 for processing your application.

We allow you to challenge the data that we hold about you and, where appropriate and in line with the terms and conditions of your Society membership, you may have the data:

  * erased 
  * rectified or amended 
  * completed 

### Privacy support

If you have an enquiry or concern about our privacy policy, please contact: 

Designation: Data Protection Officer  
Address: Society for Endocrinology, 22 Apex Court, Woodlands, Bradley Stoke, Bristol, BS32 4JT, UK  
Phone Number: 01454 642200  
Fax Number: 01454 642205  
Email: [dataprotection@endocrinology.org](mailto:dataprotection@endocrinology.org)

### Your consent to this policy

By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of information by the Society for Endocrinology as specified above. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will gain consent where appropriate and post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it.
